mongo
show dbs
use nodeqb
db.createCollection('users')
db.users.insert({name: "Ann", email: "a@g.com", role: "student", class: "wXy1z", class_title: "Physics", password: "pwdann" })
db.users.insert({name: "Bill", email: "b@g.com", role: "student", class: "wXy1z", class_title: "Physics", password: "pwdbill" })
db.users.insert({name: "ELiu", email: "e@g.com", role: "teacher", class: "wXy1z", class_title: "Physics", password: "pwdeliu" })
db.users.insert({name: "MsLee", email: "mlee@g.com", role: "teacer", class: "abc123", class_title: "Algebra", password: "pwdmslee" })
db.users.insert({name: "Ben", email: "benny@g.com", role: "student", class: "abc123", class_title: "Algebra", password: "pwdben" })
db.users.insert({name: "June", email: "june@g.com", role: "student", class: "abc123", class_title: "Algebra", password: "pwdjune" })
db.users.find().pretty()

db.createCollection('questions')
db.questions.insert({quiz_id: ObjectId("5b1c0a5136bbf1389cfdb00c"), order: 1, question:"A convex lens..", choiceA: "bulges out in the middle", choiceB: "is thinner in the middle", choiceC: "is a liquid", choiceD: "is a gas", choiceCorrect:"choiceA", author: ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bc"), included: true})
db.questions.insert({quiz_id: ObjectId("5b1c0a5136bbf1389cfdb00c") , question:"A parabolic mirror", order: 2, choiceA: "has a focus", choiceB: "caves in", choiceC: "can give a real image", choiceD: "all of the above", choiceCorrect:"choiceD", author: ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bc"), included: false})
db.questions.insert({quiz_id:ObjectId("5b1be551cd778512b8097285"), question:"Calculus is the study of", order: 1, choiceA: "tartar", choiceB: "limits", choiceC: "chemistry", choiceD: "arithmetic", choiceCorrect:"choiceB", author: ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bd"), included: false})
db.questions.insert({quiz_id:ObjectId("5b1be551cd778512b8097285"), question:"L'hopital's rule says that", order: 2, choiceA: "0/0 limits depends on num or den faster", choiceB: "hospital", choiceC: "hopping", choiceD: "lopping", choiceCorrect:"choiceA", author: ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bd"), included: true})
db.questions.find().pretty()

db.createCollection('scores')
db.scores.insert({class: "wXy1z", student_id: ObjectId("5b1cdd47a9e1c08be5eea5ba")  , quiz_title: "Gravity" , score: 95, created_at: ISODate(), details:[{question: "G is for", choiceA: "gravity", choiceB: "gravy", choiceC:"cat", choiceD:"dog", choiceStudent:"choiceB", choiceCorrect:"choiceA"}, {question: "A is for", choiceA: "bat", choiceB: "ant", choiceC:"cat", choiceD:"dog", choiceStudent:"choiceC", choiceCorrect:"choiceB"}]})
db.scores.find().pretty()



db.users.find().pretty()
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd47a9e1c08be5eea5ba"),
        "name" : "Ann",
        "email" : "a@g.com",
        "role" : "student",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "class_title" : "Physics",
        "password" : "pwdann"
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bb"),
        "name" : "Bill",
        "email" : "b@g.com",
        "role" : "student",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "class_title" : "Physics",
        "password" : "pwdbill"
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bc"),
        "name" : "ELiu",
        "email" : "e@g.com",
        "role" : "teacher",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "class_title" : "Physics",
        "password" : "pwdeliu"
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bd"),
        "name" : "MsLee",
        "email" : "mlee@g.com",
        "role" : "teacer",
        "class" : "abc123",
        "class_title" : "Algebra",
        "password" : "pwdmslee"
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5be"),
        "name" : "Ben",
        "email" : "benny@g.com",
        "role" : "student",
        "class" : "abc123",
        "class_title" : "Algebra",
        "password" : "pwdben"
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd50a9e1c08be5eea5bf"),
        "name" : "June",
        "email" : "june@g.com",
        "role" : "student",
        "class" : "abc123",
        "class_title" : "Algebra",
        "password" : "pwdjune"
}
> db.quizzes.find().pretty()
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1bcc4c74cfff4bd4df3876"),
        "title" : "Static Electricity",
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-09T13:11:21.623Z"),
        "description" : "Chapter 16",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "reviewable" : true,
        "plays" : 3
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1bcc8674cfff4bd4df3877"),
        "title" : "Magnetism",
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-09T13:11:41.539Z"),
        "description" : "Ch18~19",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "reviewable" : true,
        "plays" : 1
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1be4c68cb0a83ba4c27486"),
        "description" : "Chapter 1 Review",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "title" : "Physics Quiz",
        "plays" : 0,
        "reviewable" : false,
        "__v" : 0,
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-09T14:33:07.094Z")
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1be551cd778512b8097285"),
        "description" : "Chapter 13",
        "class" : "abc123",
        "title" : "Calculus Quiz",
        "plays" : 0,
        "reviewable" : false,
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-09T14:33:53.296Z"),
        "__v" : 0
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1c0a5136bbf1389cfdb00c"),
        "description" : "Chapter 20",
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "title" : "Mirrors and Refraction",
        "plays" : 0,
        "reviewable" : false,
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-09T17:11:45.299Z"),
        "__v" : 0
}

> db.questions.find().pretty()
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1ce075a9e1c08be5eea5c0"),
        "quiz_id" : ObjectId("5b1c0a5136bbf1389cfdb00c"),
        "order" : 1,
        "question" : "A convex lens..",
        "choiceA" : "bulges out in the middle",
        "choiceB" : "is thinner in the middle",
        "choiceC" : "is a liquid",
        "choiceD" : "is a gas",
        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceA",
        "author" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bc"),
        "included" : true
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1ce087a9e1c08be5eea5c1"),
        "quiz_id" : ObjectId("5b1c0a5136bbf1389cfdb00c"),
        "question" : "A parabolic mirror",
        "order" : 2,
        "choiceA" : "has a focus",
        "choiceB" : "caves in",
        "choiceC" : "can give a real image",
        "choiceD" : "all of the above",
        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceD",
        "author" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bc"),
        "included" : false
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1ce087a9e1c08be5eea5c2"),
        "quiz_id" : ObjectId("5b1be551cd778512b8097285"),
        "question" : "Calculus is the study of",
        "order" : 1,
        "choiceA" : "tartar",
        "choiceB" : "limits",
        "choiceC" : "chemistry",
        "choiceD" : "arithmetic",
        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceB",
        "author" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bd"),
        "included" : false
}
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1ce088a9e1c08be5eea5c3"),
        "quiz_id" : ObjectId("5b1be551cd778512b8097285"),
        "question" : "L'hopital's rule says that",
        "order" : 2,
        "choiceA" : "0/0 limits depends on num or den faster",
        "choiceB" : "hospital",
        "choiceC" : "hopping",
        "choiceD" : "lopping",
        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceA",
        "author" : ObjectId("5b1cdd4da9e1c08be5eea5bd"),
        "included" : true
}
> db.scores.find().pretty()
{
        "_id" : ObjectId("5b1ce35ca9e1c08be5eea5c4"),
        "class" : "wXy1z",
        "student_id" : ObjectId("5b1cdd47a9e1c08be5eea5ba"),
        "quiz_title" : "Gravity",
        "score" : 95,
        "created_at" : ISODate("2018-06-10T08:37:48.708Z"),
        "details" : [
                {
                        "question" : "G is for",
                        "choiceA" : "gravity",
                        "choiceB" : "gravy",
                        "choiceC" : "cat",
                        "choiceD" : "dog",
                        "choiceStudent" : "choiceB",
                        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceA"
                },
                {
                        "question" : "A is for",
                        "choiceA" : "bat",
                        "choiceB" : "ant",
                        "choiceC" : "cat",
                        "choiceD" : "dog",
                        "choiceStudent" : "choiceC",
                        "choiceCorrect" : "choiceB"
                }
        ]
}
>
